Presenters Yuen Kam-Lun, Norman Cheung Sek-Gui
Producer Yuen Kam-Lun Executive Producer Wong Siu-Ming
Planning Rico Chu Tak-On Production Manager Lee Wah
Screenplay Ho Tung Associate Production Manager Law Sau Wai
Director of Photography Eric Chu Kwok Fai
Art Direction David Lo Kin-Ming Joey Wong Styling Kenneth Yee Chung Man
Action Directors: Poon Kin Kwan, Benz Kong To-hoi, Steve Mak Fei-hung
Car Stunts: Bruce Law Lai Yin, Bruce Law Stunts Unlimited
Assistant Director Michelle Wong Yuk-Ting, Paco Yiu Fung-Suen
Editor Cheung Bei-Tak Special Effects Stephen Ma Man-Yin
BELOVED FATHER BELOVED MOTHER
Music Philip Chan Fei Lit Theme Song "Tian Di You You"
Starring Lam Ching Ying, Joey Wong, Shing Fui-On
Anthony Wong, Gabriel Wong Yat-San, Rico Chu Tak-On
Director Wilson Yip Shing Hong
我这一招鬼王煽扇
You can't escape
你还想逃吗你
my Supernatural Fan!
刺
Stab!
糗了
Shoot.
小龟
Little Turtle,
还在装
stop pretending to be asleep.
过来
Come here.
什么事啊 师傅
What is it, sifu?
蛇跑进师傅裤档里也不说一声
You didn't think to mention that a poisonous snake was in my pants?
想整师傅啊
Are you trying to test me?
怎么会呢 师傅
Sifu, why would I
这种小Case 要是告诉你的话
bother you with something so simple?
那是摆明了瞧不起你嘛
Now that would be insulting!
你练功本事有你嘴巴一半就好了
If only you were half as smart as your excuses.
那也要师傅你肯传授给我才行
Well, then you better teach me more moves, Sifu.
把东西收拾收拾
Pack up,
启程了
and let's get on the road.
里吧嗦
Such a chatterbox.
师傅
Sifu, snake! Help!
救命啊
Sifu! Help!
师傅
Sifu!
An Eternal Combat
快走啊
Come on!
师傅等一下 我还没尿完呢
Wait, sifu, let me finish!
你终于都要来找我
You've finally returned to me.
爱姬 你永远是我的
Darling, now you're mine forever.
何方妖孽
What demon are you?
师傅
Sifu, sifu...
师傅 你把他吓跑了快追啊
You've got the upper hand, let's give chase!
孽障
Demon,
我低估了你了
I have underestimated you.
低估了就再重估嘛 还愣在那干嘛
Reassess if you've underestimated. Why are you just standing around like a dummy?
大人 这下该怎么办
My Lord, what do you think?
怎么办 我怎么知道怎么办呢
What do I think? How the hell do I know?
这下又死了六个人
Six more dead!
干脆我死给你们看好了
Boy do I wish I was one of you.
我怎么这么倒霉
This is all your fault!
-来干这种鬼差事 -你在这干什么
- To do this shit. -Why are you standing here?
你是
You...you are?
马大人
Lord Ma!
下官叩见马大人
Your servant greets Lord Ma.
不要这么多礼
Quit the yammering, and lower your hands!
把双手放下
Yes, sir.
下官无能
Are you trying to get fired?
大人饶命啊
Have mercy,
你这糊涂狗官
my lord!
放着正事不干
Have mercy!
你不去抓鬼
There's a demon out there,
居然在这玩死尸
and you're in here playing with corpses?
-我不... -不什么不啊你
-No, I was-- -No? What?
这里有你说话的份吗
Who said you could speak?
你是个什么东西
What are you?
大人
Please continue,
该您啦
my lord.
你听好
Listen up!
我给你七天时间
You have seven days
把扶桑鬼给我抓回来
to bring me that Japanese Demon King!
不然自己了断
Or get a noose fitted and hang yourself!
第八天就自己了断吧
Which is to say, you should hang yourself in eight days.
自己了断
What.. . what? Hang myself"?
大人不能断 不能断呐
No, please!
圣旨到
May I drink arsenic instead?
接旨 跪
His Majesty's decree has arrived!
奉天承运
(Stuttering) His Majesty,
皇帝诏曰
the Son of Heaven, appoints
马尚峰 为官清正廉明
Ma Sheung-fung a Royal Official.
爱民如子
He loves his people as if they were his own sons,
连升三级
has been recognised.
官达一品 以资奖励
He is hereby promoted three ranks, to be a first rank official.
这下爽呆了耶
We're saved, my lord!
万岁万岁万万岁
Long Live His Majesty!
不要这么猴急啊
What's the rush?
我这还没宣读完呢
(Stuttering) I'm not finished reading.
这个 朕呢…朕
-Yes. -We... We...
朕什么
We... what?
大人 您拿反了
My lord, you have it upside down.
我知道 你认识字你念给我听
You don't think I know that? If you're so smart, you read it!
大人 能不能不念啊
May I not read it, sir?
不能
No!
-真的要念 -快点念
I really must read?
-念 -是
-and quickly too! -Yes.
朕得闻 施家镇出现扶桑鬼王
We have heard that the Demon King is in your county
为患民间 涂炭生灵
terrorizing the peasants, murdering without blinking.
特命马尚峰捉拿异族妖孽
We order you, Official Ma, to capture and contain this demon.
限期七天
We give you seven days,
不得有诶
no extensions.
行了
Stop it!
钦此啊
Here ends the royal proclamation.
Here ends the royal proclamation!
可不可以宽限两天啊
What if we had an extra day or two?
可以那才怪呢
Of course...
第八天呐
Not! You better get a noose
就要自行了断呐
fitted for yourself on the eighth day!
我马尚峰为官多年
I, Ma Sheung-fung, have been an official for many years.
虽无大功
And though I have no big contributions,
亦无大过
I have also never done anything bad.
想不到现在大祸临头了
Why is disaster striking me now?
五位夫人
My five darling wives,
我知道你们对我是爱莫能助
I know you're unable to help me.
如果你们能够帮我早就帮我了 对不对
If you could have helped me, you would have helped long ago, right?
五位夫人 陪为夫的喝杯闷酒吧
My darling wives, please drink with me.
爸爸
Papa, papa!
爸爸 你不是要给我买新衣服的吗
You said you'd buy me new clothes!
你要给我买鞋子 买玩具给我啦
Papa, you said you'd get me new shoes! Buy me toys!
不要吵啦
Shut up!
你们还怕为父的不够烦吗
Don't you know your Father is in trouble?
大人不必如此烦恼
My lord, no need to worry!
小人得知 离城三十里外有草庐居一间
Your servant has heard that 10 miles from here,
内有草庐居士
a learned man, a dragon among pigs, lives in a hut.
善于奇门遁甲 法力无边
He's a master of the supernatural, his skills are boundless.
大人 您何不亲自拜访呢
My lord, let's visit him in person.
王八蛋
Son of a bitch.
你为什么不早说
Why didn't you say anything earlier?
害我喝了一晚上的闷酒
It's your fault I've been drinking alone!
怎么这么远啊
Hey, could it be any farther?
我快累死了
I'm so fucking tired.
你不累啊
Aren't you tired?
大人呐 是您不常走路
My lord, you're just out of practice.
就快到啦
We're almost there.
到了没有啊
Are we there yet?
大人啊
My lord,
前面那座山头就是了
Just the mountain across the way.
快走啊
Then start walking!
是大人
Yes, yes.
师爷 你有没有搞错
Are you crazy?
这也能叫做房子
You call this a hut?
大人 应该是吧
I'm guessing this is it.
不是就要你好看
If it isn't, you're screwed!
师爷
Advisor,
这怎么能住人呢
how could someone live in this hut?
当茅坑还差不多啊
I'd say it's a toilet!
大人
My lord, my lord!
什么事
The Cho Lo Residence.
这间肯定不是茅坑
-What is it? -I'm sure this is not a toilet
你闻过啊
You sniffed around?
上面有写啊 您看
It's written here, see?
王八蛋
Go to hell!
你想让我出丑啊
You know I'm illiterate!
还好没有人听见
You motherfucker, thankfully no one heard that.
快去通报啊
Go announce my arrival!
通报就通报嘛
Alright, I will.
痔疮都给你踢破了
You probably kicked open my hernia.
-快点通报 -是
-Hurry up and announce! -Yes!
两广提督衙前一品金刀护卫
The Royal Guard of the First Rank, Ma Sheung-fung!
马尚峰 马大人驾到
Lord Ma has arrived!
我什么时候多了个头衔啊
Hey, when did I get that extra title?
现在流行夸张嘛
It's trendy to exaggerate.
是
Yeah?
两广提督衙前
Here is, the governor of two provinces,
变大？
Exaggerate?
怎么会这样呢
How did that happen?
大人
My lord,
这就是幻觉
this is the power of illusion.
幻觉
-Illusion? -illusion!
师爷 我们不要玩了 赶快走吧
Hey, Advisor, quit horsing around. Let's get out of here.
大人
My lord,
这也是幻觉诶
this is also magic.
王八蛋
Fuck.
大人怎么了
What should we do, sir?
没怎么 有路就走啊
Forward, what else?
-你先走 -不要那么没出息
Come, let's go together!
我当是谁呢
I was wondering what fell in,
原来是两只落水狗啊
but it turns out its two wet dogs?
-你这小杂种啊 -你这小子
-Why you... -Fuck you!
一上了岸呐 就变成落汤鸡啦
On shore you look more like wet chickens.
你这个兔崽子你敢糗我
You little shit, how dare you insult us!
-来人呐 给我修理他 -是
-Beat him up! -Yes!
王八蛋
You motherfucker,
-你是大人还是我是大人啊 -你是
-who is the boss here? -You are.
想修理我
You want to beat me up?
你做梦
You can boast about it.
小兔崽子 你不要跑
You pocket-sized twerp,
站住
-Bring it! - How are you!
小龟 休得无礼
-Where can you go? -Little Turtle, behave!
大人 是草庐居士诶
Sir, it's Cho Lo, the Tao Master.
师傅
Sifu.
未知大人驾到 有失远迎
Please forgive me for the welcome,
望大人恕罪
my lord.
大人远渡而来 令草庐蓬荜生辉
It is an honor for us that you have travelled so far.
师傅
Sifu.
请茶
Please have some tea.
还不拿杯子来
Bring another cup immediately.
师傅 我们这是穷乡僻壤
Sifu, no one ever visits us.
只有一千零两个杯
We only had the two cups.
马大人 分甘同味 请
In that case, let's share, Lord Ma.
大人
Lord,
嫌茶叶不好吗
is the tea not to your liking?
死老头 居然敢用障眼法来迷惑本官
You old weasel, how dare you try to fool me with your illusions!
不给你点颜色瞧瞧你当我是鳖十 拿刀来
How dare you take me for a fool just because I'm polite! I better stay back.
这一招啊 叫横扫干军
This style is called Horizontal Sweep of a Thousand Troops.
再使一招开天辟地让他瞧瞧
My lord, show him Dividing the Mountain.
大人呐
My lord,
雪花盖顶啊
what about Through the Roof?
好刀法诶
Amazing!
大人啊 再使那招乌龙摆尾啊
Show him your One Armed Coolie as well!
废话 你没有看到他已经被我吓呆啦
Nonsense, can't you tell that old man is frozen stiff with fear?
拿着刀
Take the guandao.
吓呆 我师傅根本没把你放在眼球里
Fear? My sifu is just embarrassed for you!
让我耍点真功夫给你瞧瞧
Let me show you some real stuff.
好让你涨知识
Broaden your horizons.
师爷 那个软趴趴的什么家伙
Advisor, what is this dangly weapon?
还不是破绳镖嘛 没什么杀伤力的
Some sort of rope dart, but not very lethal.
早说你不识货
You're as ignorant as you look.
这个东西的名称叫缨枪
This is a dart javelin.
软趴趴的还叫缨枪
Your javelin seems awfully soft.
师傅 借你的神水用用吧
Sifu, could I borrow some Magic Water?
省点用 很难练的
Be frugal, it's hard to make.
知道啦
Sure will!
绳镖 小心了
Rope Dart? Beat this!
我刺
Poke, poke.
我刺 刺 刺
Poke. Poke. Poke.
我刺
Poke
不错
It's real!
够硬吧
It sure is!
真的够硬诶
It's really hard.
大人啊 如果擦那种地方一定很够劲
My lord, if you rubbed it on your thing, imagine how hard it would get!
哪里啊
Where?
软趴趴的地方啊
Where you dangle.
还给我
Give it back to me!
还给你 还给你
Go to hell!
孩子 你不怕我踩死你
You fucking shortcake, I'll crush you!
师傅
Sifu
孩子
Boy!
你用障眼法来迷惑我 你以为我会怕你啊
You think just because you look big that I'll be scared?
大人
My lord,
搞错了
it's not
不是他们变大了 是你变小了
that they've gotten bigger. You've gotten smaller!
这不是障眼法啊
This isn't an illusion.
看看谁踩谁
Let's see who gets crushed now!
去死
Die!
小龟
Little Turtle!
不得放肆
Behave.
快点回去
Go inside.
免礼
Please rise.
居士是世外高人
You really are a learned man. I am convinced.
下官拜服
My lord,
大人过奖
you're flattering me.
-请 -您请
This way please. -You first, please.
我这次来是想请居士帮我个忙
The true purpose of my visit. Is to ask you for a favor.
-最近皇上 -不用说了
His Majesty--
马大人既然这么有决心
My lord has proven his dedication,
草庐就舍命陪君子
I'll do whatever I can to help.
不过有个条件
But I have one condition.
什么条件你说
I'll do anything!
你肯不肯牺牲
Will you sacrifice
牺牲什么 色相啊
Sacrifice what? My body?
就是你的命
The condition is your life.
我的命
My life...
你死后我会作法令你化作金甲神将
After you die, I will transform you into a gold-plated statue.
因为你身为一品武官
Because you are a high-ranking official
有皇气护身
with protection from the Son of Heaven,
鬼王拿你没办法
The Demon King cannot harm you.
加上我徒弟 成为我左右护法
Together with my student, you will be my guards.
方能消灭鬼王
This is the only way to
此外别无他法
eradicate the Demon King.
你只不过是个居士
Hey, you're only a Taoist Priest.
又不是开草药铺
You're not a pharmacist.
你不要以为我胡言乱语
Don't think I'm bullshitting.
就算你肯死也要我肯陪
Even if you're willing to die, I have to help you.
那才能有个全尸
You must keep your entire corpse.
不然你会身首异处
Otherwise your spirit and body will be separated.
你考虑清楚
Think it over.
要我的命啊
You want my life?
我才不那么傻呢
I'd be crazy to listen to you!
那只好算草庐有心无力了
Then consider me willing but unable to help.
失陪
Goodbye.
岂有此理
Nonsense...
-师爷 我们走 -是
-Advisor, let's go. -Yes, sir!
这个神水的功用太妙了
This isn't only Magic Water,
带回去可以让我金枪不倒
it's Sacred Water!
五位夫人
Even if it's improper,
为夫这次要对不起你们了
I have to move you.
过来 把你妈的牌位拿回去
Come get your Mother's spirit tablet.
是
Got it!
我要这个
I want this one!
你妈是有一颗痣的
Your Mother had a mole.
-那不是你妈妈 -还给我啦
-That's not your Mother! -Give it back to me!
我喜欢这个
I like this one!
不要吵了 反正都是妈妈拿去
You kids are so annoying! They're all mothers, just take one.
一人一个妈 有什么好争的
Your mother, your mother.
你的
Yours.
爸爸，我要尿尿
Dad I have to pee.
不要烦了
God you kids are annoying.
爸爸 我肚子好饿哦
I'm so tired, I'm so hungry!
不要吵了
What's all this ruckus!
你们这样吵 我们怎么出城嘛
I'm sleepy... We'll never get out of here at this rate.
好好好 休息一下 休息一下
Alright, let's take a break.I'm so hungry!
要不要吃香蕉啊
Eat some bananas.
要
Bananas!
人已经够衰了
What's a day without a woman?
火气又那么大
And with the future looking so bleak...
还是先进去退退火
Let's put this water to good use.
你们不要乱跑 老爸去买些吃的 知道吗
Stay put while I go get something to eat, got it?
知道
Got it!
不要吵啦
I want the biggest one!
我最大 我来分
Give it to me!
大爷 进来 坐进来
Mister!
快进来坐吧 来嘛
Come get a drink, rest awhile!
一二三四
One, two, three, four.
四三二一
Four, three, two, one.
我们有五个人
There are five of us,
可是只有四根香蕉啊
and four bananas.
那要怎么分啊
How should we share them?
没关系
Easy.
他最小 又整天尿尿
She's the youngest and always pees herself.
不给他吃
Let's skip her.
你还不是
You're exactly the same!
你最大 又整天欺负我们
You're the eldest, and always bullying us.
我看不给你吃才对呢
The way I see it, you should go without!
你们通通不要争了
You don't have to fight.
让哥哥来替你们分
Let me help you.
怎么分呢
How?
怎么等这么久
What's taking so long?
哥哥可不可以分了嘛
Can we eat yet?
-别急 要剥皮哒 -快点
-Just a minute, I have to peel it. -Hurry up!
难道连皮一起吃啊
What's taking so long?
这位大爷 干嘛这么急呀
My good sir, what's the rush?
一下子要五位姑娘 挑也得挑半天啊
You want five girls! It takes time.
我又不是要选美进宫
I'm not the Emperor looking for concubines here!
原来是马大人你呀
Oh, it's you, Lord Ma!
干嘛这身打扮呐
What's with the costume?
有什么奇怪的 没看过我微服出巡啊
What's the problem? Haven't you seen a plain-clothes officer?
是是是是是 五位姑娘马上就到了
Yes, of course, the five girls will be right here.
要不是看你有靠山 你等着吧你
If you were anyone else... You'd be waiting forever!
你们准备好了没有啊
Are you all ready yet?
准备好了
Yes!
我一定要捞个够
It'll be glorious!
你一口 我一口
A bite for you, and a bite for me.
左一下 右一下
你一口 我一口
A bite for you, and a bite for me.
上一下 下一下
A thrust for you, and a thrust for you,
前一下 后一下
and a thrust for you, and a thrust for you!
你一口 我一口
A bite for you, and a bite for me.
你也要 她也要
左 右
Left! Right!
少不了你 少不了她
A thrust for you, and a thrust for you!
马大爷可真是的 吃了什么东西了
Lord Ma is legendary! We're screwed!
怎么这么厉害呀
I'm terrified! What should we do?
-下回你去  -我不要了 会死人的
--You go first! -No, you go first!
左 右
Left! Right!
一二三四五
One, two, three, four, five.
公不公平啊
Wasn't that fair?
公平
Yes!
不得了了
It's terrible! Terrible!
马尚峰大人 马上风死掉啦
Lord Ma Sheung-fung is dead!
不得了 不得了啦
Come in, come in.
马尚峰大人 马上风死掉了呀
Bad news! Lord Ma is dead!
这下可惨咯
Lord Ma Sheung-fung is dead!
马大人死了
师傅 果然不出你所料
Sifu! It's as you predicted!
马尚峰在怡红院 在马上中风死掉了
Ma Sheung-fung died at the brothel!
他用了神水 心力交瘁
He died of over-excitement from the Magic Water.
这种是假死的现象
This is a false death.
师傅啊 我不懂诶
Sifu, I don't see why
为什么下这么大的功夫在这个呆瓜身上
we're wasting so much energy on him.
他是一品武官 孔武有力
He is a military officer.
而且又有皇气护身
He's strong and skilled, and has the emperor's protection.
终究会用得着
He's useful.
以后你两个就当我的左右护法
From now on, the two of you
跟那个扶桑鬼一决雌雄
will be my Left-Right Guards.
什么？他是我们对抗扶桑鬼的关键人物
What? He is essential in our fight against the Demon King.
现在时间无多
Time is running out.
趁药力未散 我们快点上路
He's still under the magic water's spell, let's get going.
是 师傅
Yes, Sifu.
不要看了
You can stop looking around,
马尚峰
Ma Sheung-fung
我告诉你 你在怡红院马上中风死了
I'm here to tell you you died in action in the brothel.
我已经死了
I'm dead?
你有神经病啊
You're crazy!
我马尚峰会马上中风
I am unstoppable!
你脑筋有毛病
Are you insane?
你会马上中风 我才不可能呢
You've got a screw loose! You'll die before me!
-马大人 -不要再说了
-Lord Ma, -Enough!
又想用障碍法来骗我
You're trying to fool me with illusions again?
我告诉你啊 我从小就是被吓大的
People have been trying to scare me since I was in my mother's womb!
你不信
You don't believe me?
你看看
Take a look.
怎么样啊 马大人
How does it look, Lord Ma?
又想骗我
Trying to fool me?
长得蛮像我的啊
It does look quite like me.
像你 他根本就是你
Looks like you? He is you!
又在胡说了
Nonsense,
那我是谁呢
then who am I?
你只不过是魂魄
You're the soul.
躺在那里的 是你的尸身
What you see there is your corpse.
不相信
You don't believe us?
你不会痛的
It won't hurt,
看好啊
even if I punch you!
打你一巴掌
Nothing hurts!
我锤我锤 我锤死你 我锤死你
Punches! Slaps!
你干什么 这样糟蹋我
Hey! Are you crazy? How dare you beat me up like that?
不要看了
Don't look.
僵尸怎么行呢
Hey, what can you find out with just that?
让我来
Let me!
前空翻
Front somersault!
后空翻
Back somersault!
再来大枪背呀
Body slam!
前空翻
Delightful!
来个后空翻
Another front somersault!
我踩踩踩踩 踩死你
And another back somersault! Crush, crush!
踩死你
This is so fun!
我踩死你
Stomp, wiggle, stomp, wiggle...
使出我吃奶的力量 来招狠的
This is a once in a lifetime opportunity, for the final effort,
你有毛病啊
Are you insane?
你就这样踩我 不怕我揍你啊
How dare you stomp me like that! I'll kill you!
你现在终于相信了吧
So you finally believe.
我已经死了
I'm dead?
我不要 我不想死啊
Now what? I'm really dead? I don't want to be dead!
我还不想死 我不想死啊
I don't want to be dead!
你要想办法救救我
Help me!
居士 你要救救我
Please, Taoist Priest,
你要救救我
please save me.
你不用伤心
You need not be sad.
这乃是命中注定
This was fated.
本居士看你生前不失为一个好官
I understand you were a good official in your life.
所以施法让你归神
So I have called back your spirit.
是啊 你现在是一位天神嘞
Yes, you are now a god.
难道你不觉得 你很威风吗
Don't you feel powerful?
金银二将听令
Generals Gold and Silver!
在
Yes!
Yes...
汝等追随本居士 封为左右护法
I hereby declare you my Left-Right guards.
合力消灭扶桑鬼王
To work together to kill the Demon King.
不得有误
Make no mistake.
末将愿永远追随居士左右
I vow to always remain at your side.
师傅 那个东西来了
Sifu, the demon is arriving.
小心
Be careful!
怎么办
What should I do?
退后
Retreat!
快走啊
Last one out is the loser!
她现在已经是妖姬了 笨蛋
Sisi! She's a demon concubine now, idiot.
她现在是妖姬了
-Let's go help! -Okay!
师傅 她好厉害
Sifu, she's powerful!
-小心 -是
Be careful.
想走
Where do you think you're going?
什么都看不见 怎么办
I can't see anything! Now what?
点火弹
Light the flares!
月光宝镜
Moonlight Mirror!
师傅 摆平了没有
Sifu, is it over?
没有 她会回来
No, he'll be back. Get into position for the ritual.
摆阵
Alright!
现在你们两个进入宝镜阵内
Get into position for the Treasure Mirror Ritual.
千万不要离开阵形
You must not leave your position. Otherwise,
要不然天门就会打开
the gates to Heaven will open.
到时候会一发不可收拾 切记
At that point, it'll be beyond our control.
-准备 -好
-Prepare! -Yes!
好
Yes!
点火
Light the fire!
火弹
Firebomb!
月光宝镜
Moonlight Mirrors!
天玄玄地苍苍 日月助我发神光
Heaven is vast and the Earth is ash. Sun, Moon, give me your enchanted light!
收妖
Capture the demon!
惨了
Shoot!
糗了
Oh shit!
师傅 怎么办
Sifu, now what?
放心 千万不要移位
Remain calm and stay in position!
不要 不要离阵
No! Don't leave your position!
师傅救命啊 救命啊
Sifu, help! What's happening?
师傅 怎么办
Sifu, now what?
天门开了 我也没办法啊
It's out of my hands, the gates of Heaven are open!
扶桑鬼 还不受死 更待何时
Demon King, why won't you die? What are you waiting for?
来的正好
You're right on time.
下来!
Get down!
这招武术指导好像没套过诶
Hey, this isn't what the action director planned!
我套的
I planned it.
喂 喂
Hey, hey!
想走
There's no escape!
拉好拉好 小心点
Pull!
Cut
Cut!
好了好了 不要再搞了啊
All right, don't fuck anymore.
搞什么嘛
Hey, are you kidding me?
用真剑也不说一声 屁股都开花了
Why didn't you warn me he was going to use a real sword?
这个老头谁找来的
Hey! Where's this old man from?
小乔呢
Where's Monkey?
对不起啊
Excuse me,
刚才肚子不舒服
I was just in the bathroom.
怎么样 可以拍了吗
Are we ready to shoot?
你太不敬业了 你回家好了
You're fired!
好了好了 不要吵了
All right, stop arguing.
这种拍法 我怎么来得及赶下一组戏啊
Hey man, at this rate, I'll never make it to the other set.
套好招再叫我吧
Figure it out before you call me again.
什么东西嘛
Oh please!
导演 他好像断气了
Director, I think he stopped breathing.
打电话叫救护车
Make the call then.
然后呢
Call an ambulance?
然后再打电话叫记者来做宣传
Call the journalists for the publicity!
等一下机器抬上去
Place a camera here.
人也抬上去 直接把人丢下来
Pick the guy up, then throw him down.
好 开始准备了
While we have him, let's get a second shot!
不知道诶 他今天晚上好像有事情哦
I don't know, I think she had an appointment today.
你到底有没有跟黄医生说我要找他啊
Did you really tell Dr. Wong I called?
有啊 他在开会诶
Yes, she said she's in a meeting.
开会
A meeting?
哪有那么多会要开啊
Why does she have so many meetings?
你在骗我
You liar,
你根本就是 喂
I say-- Hello?
上主的神圣 已临你们中
# The Lord God has come upon you #
上主的神圣 带来真正的幸福
X The Lord God brings true happiness X
愿主祝福你的工作
# May God bless your work #
愿主祝福你的居所
# May God bless your home #
愿主赐给你真美善
# May God gift you true perfection #
祝福你主的期望
# May God bless your hope #
祝福你主的喜乐
# May God bless your music #
祝福你主的期望
# May God bless your aspirations #
祝福你主的喜乐
# May God bless your -- #
祝福你主的希望
# May God bless your aspirations #
祝福你主的喜乐
# May God bless your joy #
神父 怎么办呐
Father, what should we do?
什...什么？
What.. What?
全能的天父
Almighty God,
求你帮助你的子民驱逐魔鬼
May you please aid your believers In exorcising these demons.
痛死我啦
That hurts!
快跑
Run!
恶魔 在万能的主面前你无所遁形
Demon! You are powerless in the face of an almighty God!
痛死我啦
It hurts!
快走啊 再不走就死定啦 快走啊
Run! What are you waiting for?
不要走啊
Don't go!
我还没有替你驱魔
I haven't exorcised the demon!
-怎么办 -我不知道啊
Now what?
有没有搞错啊
It won't open!
你们这样会把门撞坏的
Are you stupid? You'll break the door!
这不是开了吗 傻瓜
Open it like that!
-快走啊 -谢啦
-Let's go! -Thanks!
喂
Hey!
快点快点
Come on, come on.
快点把他抓回来啊
Come on, bring him back!
别跑
Stop right there!
天残脚
Huh? Iron foot?
你干什么打人啊你
Why are you attacking him? Are you crazy?
-不要再跑了 -不要跑 站住 快
-Freeze, freeze! -Where do you think you're going?
走
Let's go!
这个死老头真是神经病啊 乱打人呢 真是
He's insane! Lock him up!
何方鼠辈 竟敢如此对待本居士
Who are you with? How dare you treat me like this?
-你这家伙倒挺可爱的 -就是啊
-At least he's consistently insane. -Sure is.
告诉你 我们是香港皇家警察
We're the Hong Kong Royal Police!
你等如何处置本居士
What will you do with me?
打包上车了 走啊
Put you in a car! Let's go!
休得无礼
Where are your manners?
我要见当地的知县
I demand to see the local official!
快点替我去通报
Announce my arrival!
听见没有
Can you hear me?
神父啊
Father,
那两个不知道什么人 穿的稀奇古怪的
we've no idea who those two are. They're dressed funny too.
我怎么叫门他们都不肯开诶
They won't open the door no matter how long I knock.
你还送东西给他们吃啊
And you're still feeding them?
你怕不怕
Aren't you afraid?
神父 我们需不需要报警啊
Father, should we call the police?
我们无所不在的主连魔鬼都宽恕
If our Almighty God has space in his heart for demons,
何况他们还是人呢
who are we to disagree?
这么小的字眼睛会看坏的
The characters are so small... Bad for my eyes.
什么书啊
What kind of book is this?
我怎么看也看不懂呢
I don't understand a single word.
不看了
I give up.
这里又不知道是什么地方
Where are we?
师傅也不晓得在哪里
And where is Sifu?
我早就说过了
I told you,
你这个三寸钉有什么脑筋啊
you have a screw loose somewhere.
这是扶桑鬼的幻觉
We're in the Demon King's illusion.
这样饿下去啊
At this rate,
今天不饿死 明天一定死定了
even if we don't die today, we'll die tomorrow.
你早就死掉了
You're dead already!
你现在是天神诶
You're a god!
你没听说过 天神嗅其气 凡人食其味
Gods inhale delicious smells, people eat delicious foods.
你怎么会肚子饿呢
Why would you get hungry?
小弟兄 肚子饿了吧
Hey little guy, you must be hungry.
-来吃啊 -是啊 吃啊
-Eat up! -Yeah! Eat up, eat up.
来
It's delicious!
味道很棒的哦
No need to be polite!
不要客气 吃啊
Go on, take it!
师兄啊 你知不知道你为什么长不高
Sihing, Do you know why you're so short?
你吃独食
Because you eat alone.
不是说了吗 神只要闻闻味道
I told you gods inhale delicious smells.
我委屈点让你闻闻好啦
Here, I'll let you smell it,
怎么样啊
alright?
现在是不是感觉很饱啊
How is it? Do you feel less hungry?
师兄
Sihing,
我一点感觉都没有啊
it's not working...
那对不起了 我帮不了你忙了
Sorry, I guess I can't help.
师兄
Sihing...
我发现了一个问题诶
I've discovered a problem.
请说
Go on.
我现在深深的体会到 感觉到 领略到
I feel it very very deeply in my body
做人比做神好
it's better to be a man than a god, come!
你太贼了
Hey! No cheating!
-说好不能吃的 -给我咬一口
You can't eat this! Just sniff it!
我再让你闻一下好了
I'll let you smell it again.
大哥 可以玩了吧
Big Brother, can we start playing yet?
不是说过吗
How many times do I have to tell you,
玩这个游戏要叫我审判长吗
when we play this game, call me Your Honor?
对不起大哥
Sorry, Big Brother!
审判长
Your Honor!
下次不敢了大哥
I won't do it again, Big Brother!
审判长
SECRETARY, JUDGE, PROSECUTOR
不要怕 我可以帮你
Don't worry, I can help you.
这家伙什么罪名啊
What's his crime?
我刚刚收到消息说
I heard
他大闹医院 扰乱群众 好大罪哦
he caused a public disturbance at the hospital. It's a serious offense!
顺风耳啊
Earhustle, well done.
你收风有功 赏你一口
Take a sip.
谢谢审判长啊
Thank you, Your Honor!
现在
Now.
我告你
I hereby charge you with
制造动乱
instigating unrest...
制造动乱你认不认罪啊
Instigating unrest! Do you plead guilty?
你不说话表示默认 判你死刑
Silence means you're pleading guilty!
你有没有意见呐
I sentence you to death! How does that sound to you?
没意见
No opinion? Really no opinion?
那我们就枪毙
Execution!
DECAPITATE
对不起啊
I'm so sorry,
我帮不了你了
I couldn't help you.
预备
Ready!
开始
Action.
大哥大哥 女魔头来了啦
Big brother! The Demoness is here!
猎魔行动
Mission Demon Hunting!
大家装睡啊
Pretend to be asleep!
我睡着了
I'm asleep.
施施姑娘
Miss Sisi!
怎么你没死啊
You're alive!
你怎么了
How do you feel?
现在是午睡时间啊
It's nap time right now.
你不是施施
You're not Sisi.
你是妖姬
You're the Demon King's concubine.
草庐既然被你妖法所获
And now I am enchanted by your magic.
也没话可说
I have nothing to say.
要杀便杀
Kill me if you must,
随你处置
there's nothing to say.
我不是妖姬
I'm not a demon's concubine.
就算我是妖姬我也不会杀你的
and even if I were, I wouldn't kill you.
乖乖的上床睡觉去好不好
Now, will you be a good boy and take a nice nap?
黄医生
Dr. Wong!
黄医生呐
Dr. Wong, Dr. Wong!
你病房的那些宝贝啊
Your precious patients
经常把我的拖把拿去玩 你叫我怎么交差嘛
keep taking apart my mops! How am I supposed to do my job!?
张嫂 我会跟上面解释的
Ma'am, I'll tell my supervisors.
你先把房间收拾好吧
Just clean up their room first.
叫我做就做 那我多没面子啊
So what if you tell them... it doesn't help clean the floors.
命中
Hit the target
原来你叫草庐兄啊
So your name is Cho Lo!
果然是硬汉一条诶
You're such a brave warrior!
好硬 好硬哦
So hard, so hard.
来来来
Come here!
先喝一口啊
Take a sip!
以后我们就是好兄弟了啊
From now on, we're brothers.
好兄弟
Yeah! Good brothers!
有空的时候我们可以歇血为盟
Let's form a blood alliance when we have a spare moment.
现在是什么年代
What era are we in?
你们是什么人
Who are you people?
我现在先回答你第一个问题啊
Let me answer your first question.
现在是
It's now...
一九九一呀
1991.
一九九一
It's 1991!
再过六年我们就统统可以去移民啦
So six more years before we emigrate!
现在我回答你第二个问题
And now, for the second question.
你跟我都是同一类的人
You and I are the same kind of people.
不过外面那些傻瓜统统是叫我们白痴啊
But the crazy people outside say we're insane!
现在是谁当政
Who's the emperor now?
江…江泽民呐
Jiang... Jiang Zemin!
江泽民
Jiang Zemin?
不是李世民啦
Not Li Shimin?
李世民 已经死了好久嘞
Simon Li? He's been dead for a thousand years!
有没有看到我两个徒弟
Have you seen my two students?
有没有看到他们
Have you seen them?
徒弟
Students?
你有两个徒弟啊
You have two students?
WHERE ARE YOU?
不要吵不要吵 他来变戏法啦
Be quiet! He's doing a transfiguration!
冒烟了
Smoke up.
草庐兄
Brother Cho Lo!
你会变魔术啊
You're trained in the dark arts?
胡说 道魔不两立
Nonsense! Taoism and the dark arts are in an eternal battle.
这不是魔术 这是道术
This is not magic. It's Taoism.
道术
Taoism?
这样饿下去
To starve like this...
不要说神了
Don't talk about God
就连鬼也受不了
even a snake would die.
烤乳鸽
Roasted pigeon?
你是天神诶
I told you you're a god.
天神嗅其气 凡人吃其味
Gods inhale delicious smells.
你不用吃东西 拿来
You don't have to eat, give it to me.
好大胆 敢抢我乳鸽
How dare you steal my pigeon!
神神神 你没听过吃神啊
God, god, god... Haven't you heard of the God of Cookery?
你惨了 那是师傅的信鸽诶
You're in trouble now! This is Sifu's courier pigeon!
拿来
Hand it over!
汝等在何方
Where art thou?
异教掌门 会唱歌的
Cult leader, cult leader, cult leader?
管你什么教的
Cult leader!
那个穿白长袍的
小弟兄 你不能这样叫我啊
Little man, you can't call me that.
你可以叫我神父
You may call me
或者叫我Father
Father.
花朵
Flower?
一个大男人叫花朵 随便啦
A man named Flower? Who cares!
请问贵宝号如何称呼
May I ask where we are?
这里就是上主之家啊
This is the Lord's house.
上主之家
The Lord's house?
一定是花朵他说错了 应该是主上之家
Flower must have meant their lord's house!
SIFU, WE WAIT AT THE LORD'S HOUSE.
菠萝菠萝蜜
Prajna paramita
怎么会这样呢
It's not working...
幸好没有人看见
Thankfully no one saw that...
如果让别人看见我的糗事
that'd be so embarrassing...
叫我以后怎么出来混呢
I'd be done for!
菠萝菠萝蜜
Prajna paramita
失火喽
Fire!
失火了 在哪里
There's a fire. Where is it?
干什么 没见过啊
What? Never seen this?
当然没见过了
Of course not!
神父 你看
Look, Father!
我的上帝
Oh my God!
我的珍藏本呢
Where's my collector's edition!
是不是这本啊
Is it this one?
惨了惨了 我的漫画书被毁了
Oh no! My one comic book is done for!
怎么看这种书啊
Serves you right for reading that trash!
发生什么事情啦
What happened?
这样怎么行呢
Is that really okay?
当然不行啦
Of course it's not okay!
赶快滚蛋啊！
You're no longer welcome here!
乳鸽香 乳鸽甜 我吃乳鸽馋死你
Yummy yummy in my tummy,none for the puppy next to me.
-香啊，香啊 -给我一口!
-Sidai, Sidai. -let's share!
吃一小口嘛 你不要拿那么高嘛 师弟
You can have it if you can reach it!
-你想吃啊 门都没有 -你放下来一点
Hey, hey!
-来啊来啊 -吃一小口 师弟师弟
You're awful, why won't you hand it over!
喂 喂
Hey, hey!
给马尚峰吃啦
You were eaten by Ma Sheung Fung?
那两个混蛋去哪里了
Where are those two?
就只知道疯 一点正事不会干
What shoddy work... Looks nothing like a pigeon.
主上之家
Their lord's house?
难道那两个混蛋在皇上那里
Could the two be with the Emperor?
我是超人Super Man
I'm superman!
-快点走啦 -我飞
-Let's go. -Walk!
-我飞 我飞飞飞 -想跑啊你
-Walk! Walk! -Superman has to fly!
喂 别跑 你不要跑 过来
-Hey, stop!
你还跑啊
Stop!
值班人员请带两个护士到大门口接收病人
Nurse-on-duty! Please admit the patient at the main gate!
这么晚了还要我们出去接收病人 有没有搞错啊
How could they ask us to admit a patient at this hour?
-就是嘛 当我们是超人呐 -真够笨的
-Exactly! -Ludicrous!
人家都不要睡觉啦
We need to rest too!
大侠
Here comes superman!
你要去哪里啊
Where you off to?
还穿古装诶
You're dressed nicely...
你知道我们今天开化妆舞会啊
How did you know we were having a party?
主上之家在哪里啊
Do you know where the Emperor lives?
我知道 在中南海嘛
I know, in the Mediterranean Sea!
中南海在哪里
And where's that?
我知道啊 我带你去好不好啊
I can take you there, alright?
草庐兄啊 我等你好久好久了耶
Brother Cho Lo, we've been waiting so long for you!
-对啊对啊 -你不是说带我去中南海吗
This is it?
有桌子有蓝色 这么大就是中南海嘛
There's orange, there's green, and we're the ocean!
对啊对啊 草庐兄啊
Brother Cho Lo,
欢迎你来参加我们的舞会
welcome to our ball!
我们一起来跳舞 跳舞
Let's dance! Party!
一群疯子
They're all crazy!
幻术箱
Illusion box?
扶桑鬼 你终于出现了
Demon King, you've finally revealed yourself!
我们来拔河好不好
Let's play Tug-of-War!
来来来
Yeah!
拔河
Tug-of-War!
嘿!他会拉手风琴!
Hey! He can play the accordion!
大哥 老道士好棒哦
Big Brother, this Taoist geezer is amazing!
什么老道士啊
What Taoist geezer?
他现在是我们的大大哥
He's now our Big-Big Brother!
你们干什么
Hey! What are you doing?
怕怕怕怕
The riot police are here! Scary, scary!
护士来了 护士来了 好可怕额
The riot police! Scary!
一直到现在 我们还没查出你的身份
Until now, we still don't know who you are.
只知道你是一个电影武行
We only know you're a stuntman.
干嘛这样看着我啊
Why do you look at me like that?
我早跟你说过 我不是妖姬
I told you, I'm not a demon's concubine.
也不是施施
Nor am I Sisi.
我是GIGI
My name is Gigi.
我是这家医院的心理医生
I'm a psychiatrist here.
我们会尽量帮助你的
I will do my best to help you.
大家都是同道中人
Since we're cut from the same cloth,
没必要绑着我
why keep me tied up?
你放心 他们等下就会放你的
Don't worry, they'll let you go soon enough.
你不要害怕
No need to be so afraid.
你
You...
是不是很讨厌电视啊
Do you really hate TV?
还是讨厌里面的画面
Or do you hate the image?
幻术箱
Illusion box?
你快点下来啊
Come down!
你在上面那样子很危险的
That's dangerous!
你赶快下来啊
Come down now!
怎么样没事吧
Are you alright?
快起来吧
Here's let's get you up.
你不是妖姬就肯定是施施
If you're not a demon, then you're Sisi.
不过我觉得很奇怪
But when did you achieve this level of Tao?
你的道行什么时候练得这么高
With a mere wave of your hand,
竟然不费吹灰之力
you were able to
能将鬼王呼之则来挥之则去
summon and dismiss the Demon King.
其实我也很想知道
Actually, I'd also like to know
你为什么一下子叫我施施
why do you sometimes called me "Sisi"
一下子又叫我妖姬呢
and sometimes a demon?
能不能告诉我
Can you tell me?
可以
Of course.
怎么是你
-Oh, it's you. -Yes.
大大哥
Big-Big Brother.
快点快点 来叫人呐
Greet him!
大大哥
-Big-Big Brother... -Rise.
起来吧 叫我老道士就行了
Just call me Taoist Geezer.
草庐兄啊
Brother Cho Lo,
你不是说你要出去救你徒弟吗
I thought you were going to rescue your students?
那我们特别来救你的呀
We came to save you!
你的遗产全带来了
We brought your belongings.
谢谢各位
Thank you.
大哥 外面没人
Big Brother, there's no one here!
-外面没有人谁都知道啊 -是
Of course there's no one. Even a crazy person could tell.
大大哥啊 你现在就快点走吧
Big-Big Brother, you better get going.
门口啊就在外头
The gate is that way.
是啊
Yeah,
再晚一点呐 恐怕就来不及了
or it'll be too late!
来不及了
Too late!
各位兄弟
Brothers,
草庐日后一旦找回两个徒弟
once I have found my two students,
一定会来救你们出去
I will be back to rescue you.
才不要
Please don't!
怕怕
Scary, scary!
外面的人比我们还傻
People out there are crazier than we are!
外面啊 江湖险恶
It's dangerous out there! Here, take this.
这个你就先带着吧
you don't need to fold courier pigeons anymore!
是啊 你先拿着吧
Yeah, with this,
以后啊 你就不用折纸鸟了
You won't have to origami birds anymore
对对对
Yeah!
大恩不言谢
It's too great a gift.
就此拜别
I bid you goodbye.
各位请了
Adieu!
再见了 再见
Goodbye!
大大哥
Big-Big Brother!
再见了大大哥
Goodbye! Big-Big Brother!
珍重
Goodbye!
再见
Take care.
大大哥再见
Take care!
强哥 帮我开一下门好不好
Brother Keung, please open the gate.
没问题 搞这么晚啊
Sure thing, why are you so late?
是啊 吃宵夜没有
Have you had your midnight snack?
吃过了
Yeah!
-谢谢啊 -不客气
-Thank you! -No worries.
GIGI 怎么这么晚还没走啊
Hey, Gigi, why so late tonight?
是啊 本来很早就可以走的
I was planing on leaving earlier,
后来跟一个病人谈点事情
but I ended up speaking with a patient
所以耽误到现在
for a very long time.
GIGI 你的行李箱没有关好诶
Gigi, your trunk isn't closed.
早点回去休息吧 晚安
Get home safe, goodnight!
谢谢你啊 晚安
Thanks, goodnight.
今晚不知道怎么搞的
What's wrong with tonight...
小姐 麻烦驾照借我看一下
Miss, your license please.
小姐 后座看一下吧
Miss, may I take a look?
好啊
Sure.
这小狗挺可爱的嘛
The puppy is pretty cute!
小土狗 便宜货
It's just a cheap mongrel.
土得可爱啊
Still pretty cute.
你还真有一套呢
Not bad...
什么时候上了我的车 我都不知道
How did you get in here without me knowing?
看你蛮乖的 我就带你回家去啦
Since you're such a good boy... I'll take you home.
来 小狗狗乖乖的待在这啊
Good boy, stay.
肚子饿了吧 我给你弄点吃的
If you're hungry, I'll get you something to eat.
狗狗
Puppy,
乖
Good boy.
乖啊
Good boy...
GIGI啊 我是梁医生
Gigi, it's Dr. Leung.
你那份报告我已经看过了
I read your report.
根据精神病科交来的资料 可能有点问题诶
According to the information from Psychiatry, there may be some issues.
我看最好还是等开会的时候
Let's let the Dean decide
由院长来决定好了
when we meet.
GIG啊 我是阿英
Gigi, it's Ah Ying.
这个星期五晚上七点
Don't forget
我们要跟张医生开会哦
we have a meeting with Dr. Cheung
不要忘记了
at 7p.m. this Friday.
GIGI 我知道你在逃避我
Gigi, I know you're hiding from me.
我打电话到医院去 你也不肯接
You won't answer when I call the hospital.
我告诉你 你这样做是没用的
Your resistance is futile. Let me tell you--
你放开我啊
No! What are you doing? Let me go!
不要
No!
-不要 -干什么
-No. -What are you doing?
你以前不是很喜欢这样玩的吗
I used to love playing with you like this!
-不要 -现在连亲一下都不行了
-No. -And now you won't even kiss me back!
不要
No.
GIGI
Gigi!
我把你吓着了是不是
Did I scare you?
好 送你一束花
Here's a flower for you.
不要
No.
GIGI
Gigi,
你知不知道我现在还是一样的爱你呀
you know I've never stopped loving you.
我已经跟你说过多少次了
How many times do I have to tell you,
我们两个已经完了
we're through!
我早就对你死心了
I no longer love you!
你不要再缠着我好不好
Stop tormenting me!
你骗人
You're lying!
我知道你还是爱我的
I know you still love me!
以前是我不对 我不长进
I know I was a little crazy before...
但是我可以改呀
but I can change!
答应我 嫁给我
Believe me, marry me.
-回到我身边来 GIGI -不要
-Come back to me. -No.
GIGI
Gigi!
不要
No.
你发神经啊
Are you crazy?
你喜欢打是不是
You like hitting?
继续打呀 打
Keep hitting!
你走开 走开
Go on!
不要 你走开
No!
臭狗 我摔死你我
You fucking dog, I'm going to kill you!
怎么变大了
What the...?
不要追我
Stop following me!
想不到是你救了我
I can't believe you saved me.
谢谢你 乖狗狗
Thank you.
你先去喝一点牛奶 我等下再来看你哦
Drink some milk first. I'll be right back.
你看看你呀
Hey, look at you!
喝的一身都是牛奶脏兮兮的
You're covered in milk!
怎么样 吃饱了吧 我帮你擦擦干净啊
What a good puppy... Let me clean you up.
乖
Good.
狗狗乖
Come--
我帮你擦擦干净啊
Let me clean you up.
小笨瓜
What a silly puppy...
救命啊
Help!
小姐 小姐啊
Miss,
我不是故意要吓你的
I didn't mean to scare you!
小姐啊 我今天所说都是干真万确的
Miss! Miss, everything I told you today is true.
你走 不要听你解释
Leave! I don't want to hear it!
我逃出来的原因
I escaped from the hospital
是要找回我那两个徒弟
to find my two students.
不想他们被扶桑鬼抓去啊
I don't want them to be caught by the Demon King.
你要相信我
Please believe me.
你走 你走啊你
Leave, leave!
好 我走
Alright, I'll leave. I'm leaving!
玉佩还给你啊
I'm returning your jade amulet.
就放在桌子上
I left it on the table.
你前世乃宜水县施家镇人
In your past life, your name was Sisi.
原名叫施施
Hailing from Sika County.
被鬼王山的扶桑鬼垂涎迫婚
You were forced to marry the Demon King.
父母双双死于鬼王淫威之下
The Demon King killed both your parents.
而你为了挽救全镇的百姓
In exchange for the safety of the entire county,
所以忍辱下嫁
you agreed to marry him.
在途中你想刺杀鬼王
Your attempt to murder him failed.
结果失败
He stole your soul,
最后还让鬼王收服
and ultimately,
变成妖姬
you became his demonic concubine.
你怎么在这待了一夜啊
You've been here all night?
本来想走的
I had planned on leaving,
下了一夜的雨 没有走
but then it rained all night.
声音怎么那么沙哑呢
Your voice is cracked.
没办法 吠了一夜
Yes, well... I barked all night.
那你为什么不上来避避雨
Why didn't you come up to get out of the rain?
不太好
That's improper,
男女授受不亲
Men and women
何况同处一室
should keep a distance.
昨天晚上真不好意思啊
I'm sorry about last night.
没关系
It's fine.
地上怎么会有那么多纸鹤啊
Why are there so many paper cranes on the ground?
这些纸鹤是我用来跟徒弟通消息用的
It's my method of communicating with my students.
你知道吗
You know what?
我的法术啊
But my powers
一遇到雨水就会失灵的
are useless in the rain.
对了
Oh, yes.
我收到我徒弟的消息
Their last message said they were at the local lord's residence.
知不知道主上之家在哪里
Do you know where the local lord lives?
主上之家
The lord's residence?
我去问问人家才知道
Let me ask around,
你放心 我会帮你找的
I'll help you look.
对了 外面的人到处都在找你
Oh yes, they're looking for you.
你还是先到我家里面去避一下
You better stay at mine today.
这是我大门的钥匙 你会不会用啊
Do you know how to use my keys?
会 我看你开过
Yes, I saw you use it.
这一支
It's this one.
那我先回医院去了
I have to get to the hospital.
你还在那边干嘛
Hey! Why are you still standing around?
今天晚上我一定会陪你去找你徒弟的
I promise to help you look for your students tonight, okay?
OK
Okay!
你到底行不行啊
Your transfiguration skills suck!
放了一整天了 没有半只飞上天的
You've been at it all day, and nothing flies.
大清早的你鸡毛子喊叫的
Hey, it's still early!
再怎么说我小龟也是你师兄啊
I'm still your sihing, show some respect!
师兄 师你妈个头啦
Sihing? What a load of crap!
你要搞清楚啊
If it
要不是下一场大雨
weren't for the rain
我小龟怎么会在你面前丢人呢
every single one of them would fly!
有句话说的很有道理啊
There's a saying that makes sense
拉不出屎来怪茅房
A bad workman blames his tools!
这句话最适合你了
That phrase was made for you!
我老实告诉你好了
Don't you know
师傅的法术最忌讳碰到水
our powers don't work
只要一碰到水就破法了
in the rain!?
你搞清楚了没有
Get it?
师兄 你说完啦
Sihing, are you done?
说完了
Yes.
你说完了
Good,
我已经饿的前胸贴后背了
because I'm hungrier than a dead dog.
拜托 你救救我好不好
I beg you, save me!
师兄
"Sihing"
南无阿弥陀佛
Namo Amitabha?
有了
I've got a plan!
谢谢
At home,
在家靠父母
you rely on your brothers.
出外靠朋友
Out in the world, you rely on your friends!
今天我们路过贵宝地 欠缺盘缠
Today, we have journeyed into your fair town
有钱的捧个钱场 没钱的捧个人场 谢谢
seeking nothing but two small meals.
刚才我师弟表演那两下没有什么
We're just warming up!
好戏还在后头呢
We've saved the best for last.
他为什么躺着?
Why is he lying down?
他能举起那块厚板吗?
Can he even lift that slab?
闪到一边去
Get off.
你到底行不行啊
This strongman is more like it!
他全身都是红色的!
He's all red!
这种事可不是闹着玩的
Can he really handle it?
出了人命怎么办哦
Don't kill anyone!
你可得小心点
He can't even lift the hammer!
拉屎！
Get shit!
你给我躺下
Lie down!
师弟啊 你留心点啊
Be careful, Sidai!
打不碎不要钱
No charge if I don't break it in one go!
让我们看看这个
Let's see this!
师弟
Sidai!
打碎啦
How's that!?
谢谢 谢谢 棒极了
Thank you, thank you. Awesome!
我们不会再挨饿了 谢谢啊
We won't be hungry again! Thank you, thank you.
警察来啦 快闪呐
Cops, cops! Stop right there!
再来一次
One more...
演工地秀啊
Hey! What are you doing? Putting on a big show?
起来起来
Get up!
街头卖艺 赚点盘缠啊
Just busking for our next meal...
你敢消遣我 带走
Busking? Arrest him!
走
Let's go!
放开我
Get up!
Let go of me!
呼叫总部 召集人马 召集人马
Over, over! Backup, backup!
马
Backup?
放开我
Who are you people?
你没事吧
Are you alright?
师弟啊
Let's go.
银票没有用 白银才值钱呐
Paper money is useless, only silver coins count! Money!
没用
Move!
师傅
Sifu...
不要叫了 叫的我心都烦啦
Stop... your whining Is driving me crazy.
-师傅 -好好好 我带你去找师傅嘛
-Sifu... -I'm taking you to sifu now.
你们拍戏啊
Are you crazy?
请问绿水精神病院怎么走
Excuse me, where is the Green Waters Insane Asylum?
在那边 你们俩去最适合了
You're going the right way, you certainly belong there!
谢谢啊
Oh, uh, thanks.
GIGI 我现在正式向你求婚
Gigi, I am now officially proposing to you.
GIGI
Gigi,
Gigi!
来 送给你
For you!
阿彬
Ben--
你放过我吧 好不好
Please let me go, alright?
放过你
Let you go?
NO
No!
还想跑 你跑不掉的
No need to run, you won't get away!
你跑到天涯海角我还是会追到你的
I'll find you even at the ends of the earth!
你回来啦
You're back.
你怎么穿这个样子啊
Why are you dressed like that?
我的衣服昨天晚上淋湿了
My clothes were wet.
这电视是你开的吗
You turned on the television?
是啊 我看过你开那幻术箱我就会开啦
Yes. I had seen you turn on the illusion box, so I knew how.
这牛奶也是你喝的
And you had the milk?
是啊 昨天晚上我喝过了
Yes, I had some last night,
很好喝诶
and it was pretty good.
你真是个聪明的古代人呐
You're a smart, ancient man.
这么快就学会了那么现代化的东西了
You picked everything up so quickly.
对了
Oh yes,
我刚才开车的时候啊
On my way home,
在公路上看到你徒弟了
I think I saw your two students on the highway.
真哒
Really?
你怎么知道是他们
How did you recognise them?
穿着啊身材啊 都跟你说的一模一样
By their clothing and behavior... just as you said.
你真的见过他们
You really saw them?
别说了 走吧
Come, let's go find them.
不行啊 我不能这样见他们
No. I can't let them see me like this.
没看见他们呐
I don't see them.
我刚刚明明是在这里看到他们的
I saw them around here.
我们到那边去看看吧
Let's go look over there.
他们在那边
They're over there!
这里很难过去啊
It's very hard to get there.
你干什么
Hey, what are you doing?
喂
Hey!
拍电影了不起啊
You think you can do anything just because it's for the movies?
小龟 尚峰
Little Turtle! Fung!
尚峰
Fung!
师傅
Sifu?
-师傅 -小龟
-Sifu! -Little Turtle!
真的是师傅
It's really sifu!
小龟
Sifu!
师傅
真的是你啊
Sifu!
师傅 我以为我再也看不到你了
Sifu, where have you been? I thought we'd never see you again!
你们两个没事吧
Are you alright?
没事
We're fine, we're fine.
当然没事啊师傅 这几天又累又饿
Of course we're fine, sifu!
有人抱总比自己走的好啊
We've been tired and hungry, it's nice to be carried.
-你居然敢骗我 -不要乱来啊
-You lied to me! -Watch yourself!
师傅在这里哦
Sifu is here!
你害的我双手都快抱酸了
My arms are numb from carrying you!
-你是不是要讨打啊 -师傅
-How could you! -Sifu.
在师傅面前没大没小的
You're wasting your energy fighting each other?
你们两个废物 我不想看见你们
The two of you are useless. I'm leaving.
师傅
Sifu, don't leave!
师傅 你不要走嘛师傅
Sifu! Sifu, don't leave!
等等我
Wait for me!
你这个蠢货
You stupid carriage!
师傅
Sifu, sifu! Don't go!
师傅 你不要走
你要是再走 我再也看不到你了
If you leave, we'll never find you! Sifu, I promise to behave.
师傅
Sifu.
-我以后再也不敢了 原谅我 -不要哭了
-I'll be good, forgive me. -Don't cry.
尚峰
Fung!
你又跑去哪里啊
Where do you think you're going?
你们师徒重逢 我为你们高兴
I'm happy you two are reunited.
但是 人鬼殊途 终须一别啊
But how long can ghosts and humans stay together? I should take my leave.
师傅 从一开始啊我就没有说溜过嘴诶
Sifu, I did as you said, I didn't tell him anything!
你真是自作聪明
God, you're so stupid.
神如果腾云驾雾的 还用走这么累
Gods can ride the clouds,
还不止这些
so why are you walking like a lost dog?
连我的信鸽都吃掉了
Also, you ate my courier pigeon!
那我是没死啊
So I'm not dead?
我是人
I'm human?
我还是人
I'm really human!
你放手啊
Let go!
你放开我
你放开我啊
Let go of me!
上车 上车啊
Relax, relax!
喂
Hey!
那不是妖姬吗
The Demon's concubine!
什么妖姬啊
Demon's concubine? That's Sisi!
-是施施姑娘 -就是妖姬嘛
-She's a demon! -It's Si--
两个都不是是GIGI姑娘
She's neither. She's Miss Gigi.
她有危险 我们快去追
She's in danger, let's go.
师傅 我们又不知道她在哪 怎么追啊
Sifu, go where though?
师傅
Sifu--
这是什么
What's this?
Lighter（打火机）
A Lighter.
上次烤你的信鸽就是用它 很好用诶
Stole it when I was roasting the pigeon. It's super useful.
你看是不是
See?
这里就是主上之家
Hey, it's the lord's house!
-主上之家 -是啊
-The lord's house? -Yes.
我们快去
Then let's go!
师傅你会走吗
Sifu, you know how to get there?
路在嘴上
We'll ask for directions.
师傅你落伍了 路在手上
Sifu, you're outdated. We can ask for a ride.
快拦车啊
Hail a cab!
你不要用这种眼神看着我
Don't look at me like that.
我将会融化在你深情的目光中
I will melt in your loving gaze.
乖乖 不要动 不要动
Don't move...
你是我心目中的公主
You are my princess.
长平公主
Princess Chang-ping...
你放过我吧
Let me go!
我求求你 你放过我
Please, let me go! Let me go!
我告诉你
Let me tell you,
我们两个永远不会分开的
Till death do us part!
不要怕
Don't be scared.
这个吻是向你赎罪的
This kiss absolves you.
走
Walk!
你放手 你放手啊你
Let go, let go!
跑 看你往哪跑
Where do you think you're going?
跟我来
Come with me, come with me!
看什么 弹啊 快弹啊
Play, play!
唱歌
Sing.
唱歌啊
Sing!
走 往哪走
Run? Where can you run?
疼不疼啊
Does it hurt?
好乖好乖
So good, so good
不要哭 不要哭了啊
Don't cry, good girl,
婚礼马上就要开始了
the wedding is about to start.
不是叫你别走 叫你别走的吗
I told you not to run, I already told you!
你要走到哪去呢
Where do you think you're going?
我跟你说过多少次了
Where would you go?
继续弹 用点感情弹 继续弹呐
Keep playing! With feeling! Good girl, don't cry.
继续唱
Keep singing.
告诉他们 你愿意
Tell them you agree,
告诉他们 你愿意嫁给我
tell them you want to marry me.
说 我愿意
Say it! "I do!"
-说 -不要
-Say it! -No...
说
Say it!
说你愿意嫁给我
Say, "I do!"
说
Say it! Say it!
说我愿意
"I do!"
说说你愿意嫁给我
Say it! Say you agree to marry me!
说
Say it! Say, "I do!!"
Say it!
我愿意
Say, "I do!"
把戒指戴上
Put this on!
戴上
Put it on!
GIGI
Gigi,
Gigi!
Delta Dawn 你戴的是什么花
# Delta Dawn, what's that flower you have on #
那是一朵随时光流逝而凋谢的玫瑰吧
# Could it be a faded rose from days gone by? #
我是不是听你说过 他今日要来与你相会
# And did I hear you say he was a-meeting you here today #
带你一起去他天上的殿堂
# To take you to his mansion in the sky? #
阿彬
Ben!
不要
Don't...
我会为爱付出一切
I will sacrifice everything for love.
因为我知道什么叫做爱
Because I know what Love is.
我在雨中歌唱
# I'm singing in the rain #
我爱上了你
I'm fall in love with you!
阿彬 不要啊
Ben, no!
停车 快停车
Stop, stop!
你不要走
You won't get away!
你跑不掉的
我会追到你
I'll catch you!
GIGI姑娘 你没事吧
Miss Gigi!
阿彬他自杀死了
Ben killed himself!
那个畜生在那边
The beast is over there!
他的尸体现在已经变成了魔了
And his corpse became this demon!
-尚峰 小龟 -是
-Fung, Little Turtle! -Yes!
你们先向正北走
Go to true north first.
知道了师傅
Got it, sifu.
我会引他去北斗宝穴
I'll lure him to where the Big Dipper marks the spot!
孽畜 你还不死
Beast! This time, we'll kill you.
-畜你妈个头 快走啊 -小心点啊
-Beast your ass, let's go. -Be careful!
拍戏很辛苦噢
It's sure hard making movies, right?
我以前呐也拍过戏诶
I used to be in movies too!
找到没有
Have you got it yet?
你没看到我在找啊
I'm looking!
快点找啊
Look faster!
你们不相信呐
You don't believe me?
我的名字叫成虎
I'm Wong Four!
以前在邵氏当过武侠明星的
I used to be an action star at Shaw!
前面左边 左转呐
Left, go left!
-左转左转 -前面不能左转呐 老哥
-Left right ahead. -You can't turn left there.
叫你左转你就左转 不然你要倒大霉的哦
I told you to turn left or you're fucked!
-快点呐 -好 倒霉我认了
-Fuck it. -then. Just straight ahead,
停车
stop the carriage!
下车下车 快点快点
Get off the carriage, come on!
这里就是北斗宝穴
This is where the Big Dipper marks.
那是浚深车房诶
It's a car lot.
管你是炮房门房 一样要付钱诶
Hey! I don't care if it's the morgue or the artillery, pay up!
两广总督也要付钱啊
Are you kidding me? I'm the governor of two provinces!
港督都还要付钱呢
Even the Governor has to pay!
你比我还凶啊
You're so mean.
好了算了 就付给你了
No way around it then.
这可是血汗钱哦
It's hard earned money!
够不够啊
Is that enough?
-算了 -白痴
-I'll take it! -Idiot
这边 这边
This way...
找到没有啊
Have you found it yet?
不对 又到那边去了
No, this way, this way.
这边 这边
你颠来颠去干什么 不会用走的
Hey, shortcake! You're taking us in circles, let's just walk straight.
你懂个屁啊
What do you know?
你懂的话你来找
If you knew, you'd navigate!
-叫 -真讨厌
-Follow me! -What a nuisance!
好好 走走走
-Come. -This way, this way.
这边这边这边
No, that way, that way.
右边右边右边
Right Right Right
不对啊 又跑左边来啦
Not quite... This way...
-你晃来晃去的带我们逛公园啊 -不要吵
-Is this fun for you? -Shut up!
这里是最安全的
This is the safest spot, stay here.
找东西给她掩护
Hey, find somewhere to hide her.
-再给你个小的 -躲在里面
-This is for you. -Hide here and don't move.
-千万不要出来 -躲低一点 低一点啊
-Stay hidden, okay? -Get down.
快走啊
Let's go.
师兄啊 师父到现在没来会不会出事啊
Sihing, Sifu is taking so long... What if he's in trouble?
呆子 师傅武力高强怎么会出事呢
You're crazy, Sifu is so powerful, what could happen to him?
武力高强有个屁用啊
Even though Sifu is so powerful,
我两广总督坐车还不是要付钱
we still had to pay for that cab.
对 如果恶魔来了 师傅还没赶到
That makes me think, what if the demon gets here before Sifu?
我们手无寸铁是会吃亏的
We're unprepared. We'd be at a disadvantage!
我看啊 还是找个武器防身吧
Let's find something to protect ourselves.
走
Let's go.
-师傅 -师傅 我们好担心你
-Sifu! -Sifu, we were so worried!
好了 不要多说马上准备
We have to get to work.
准备宝镜阵
-Prepare for the Moonlight Mirror ritual! -Yes!
恶魔来了
Here comes the demon!
宝镜拿出来
Bring out the moonlight mirrors!
小心
Be careful!
你看我干什么
What do you think I'm doing?
师兄
Sihing!
Sihing...
-师兄 你没事吧 -才怪
-Are you alright? -It's a miracle
你以为我是你啊
I'm fine, I'm not you!
块头这么大 还有皇气保护着
You're big, strong, and have the Emperor's protection!
-摆阵 -是
-To your positions! -Yes!
-宝镜呢 宝镜呢 -惨了
-Where are the Moonlight Mirrors? -Shit...
在那边
Over there!
惨了惨了 师傅不能沾水的
We're doomed! Sifu can't get wet!
怎么办
Now what?
这样下去 师傅会变形的
If we keep going, Sifu will transform!
快想想办法啊
Think of something!
你有皇气 不能打也撑得住啊
Go stall for time, the Emperor's protection should keep you safe.
行不行啊
Are you sure?
我不知道
I don't know.
拼一下了
Worth a try!
好
Alright!
师傅
Sifu!
-走开 -我不走
Get out of here!
-Leave! -No!
走开啊
要死也要死在一块
If you die, we'll die together!
-你走啊 -我不走
-Leave! -No!
-我不走 -快走
Leave!
师弟
Sidai!
走啊 走啊
Run, run!
师弟
Sidai!
快走
Run!
我跟你拼啦
To the death!
小龟
Little Turtle!
想不到你真刺杀我
Beloved...
爱姬
I die by your sword...
居士
Taoist priest!
小姐
Miss--
你没事吧
Are you alright?
居士
Taoist priest?
队长
Sir,
在现场发现了一把东洋刀
we found a Japanese sword at the crime scene.
有没有伤者
Is anyone injured?
没有 不过现场像经过世界大战一样
Nope, but the scene is messier than Big Goof's home.
继续找
Keep looking,
是 长官
Yes, sir!
马上封锁现场
Ma Sheung-fung lock down the crime scene.
-送这位小姐去医院 -是
-Please take this lady to the hospital. -Yes, sir!
小姐 请跟我来
Miss, please come with me.
漫漫长路
不堪回首
剩一个寂寞的人独对天地悠悠
多少痴缠
多少烦忧
叹一声短促如梦
遗憾却是不休
爱假如不属于我说什么天长地久
爱说爱梦说梦一雾已经足够
爱不是占有爱不能强求
可以付出可以不能收